POOJA UMATHE

197 Academy Street, Apartment 204, Jersey City, New Jersey, USA - 07306

Contact: 201-238-4800 • pumathe@saintpeters.edu • https://www.linkedin.com/in/poojaumathe/ https://github.com/poojaumathe

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly self-motivated and detail-oriented Data Scientist with 3 years of professional experience focusing on Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Natural Language Processing (NLP), Data Mining using structured and unstructured data along with strong multitasking, problem-solving and leadership skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Language: Python (libraries - Pandas, Scipy, Statsmodel, Seaborn, Tensorflow, Matplotlib, Plotly, Xgboost, Pytorch, Sklearn, Keras, Numpy, NTLK), R, MATLAB, C, C++ and Visual Studio

Database Management System: MySQL, Postgres SQL, RDBMS, AWS, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Bigquery

Tools/Software: Jupyter Notebook, Tableau, Qlik, Advanced Excel, OpenCV, Google Analytics, Power BI, Pyspark

Courses: Data Mining, Machine Learning, Big Data and Data Management, Data Analysis and Decision Modeling, Data Visualization, Predictive Analytics and Modeling, Statistical Programming, Business and Marketing Analytics, Big Data Analytics, Data law and Ethics, Financial Modeling and computing.

EDUCATION

Saint Peter's University, New Jersey, USA **Master of Science**

Feb 2020 (Anticipated)

GPA 4.0

Major: Data Science

Nagpur University, Maharashtra, India

June 2015 **GPA 3.5**

Bachelor of Engineering (Graduated with first class)

Major: Electronics Engineering

RESEARCH PROJECTS

- Sentimental Analysis on Twitter data
- Natural Language Processing (NLP) on Amazon Data.
- Movie Recommendation System
- Neural Networks (Deep learning with Keras) for Image Recognition
- Regression (Prediction of house prices) (Prediction of Sales and Store Locations for Restaurant)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Extensive Business Solutions Corp, New York, USA Data Scientist

September 2019-Present

April 2019-Present

Solve client business challenges through scalable and repeatable data workflows by implementing machine learning algorithms. Support hypothesis definition, data gathering, data transformation/wrangling, model training and tuning, deployment of production scoring for classification models.

Saint Peter's University, New Jersey, USA

Graduate Research Assistant- Department of Data Science

Research on various type of investment plans for asset allocation that would perform in all economic conditions for age group 50-70.

Siddhesh Construction and Engineering, Maharashtra, India **Data Analyst**

April 2017-December 2017

Analyzed data to provide strategic and tactical input and direction, monitored and maintained data infrastructure, quality and visualization to effectively plan budgets and cost analysis, improving efficiency by 15%.

Embedded Galaxy Technologies, Maharashtra, India

August 2015-April 2017

Junior Data Engineer

Developed, deployed, and maintained the data products and systems. Supported new feature developments and data sources for data collection, reporting, and analysis platforms.

PUBLICATIONS

Assistive System for Visually Disabled Person through RFID devices, International Journal of Advent Research in Computer and Electronics (IJARCE) (March 2015)

CERTIFICATION & TRAINING

Bloomberg Market Concepts Certification | October 2019 Google Analytics Certification | October 2019 **Software Testing and Data Analysis** | December 2015